There are a number of nuances in wood cut print making, and it has to deal to a large degree with your materials and techniques and how you go about printing your block of wood.
Here, is two prints, each is on a different type of paper.
This is a kitty coda, which is a Japanese paper.
And this is a western reeves light weight paper.
They're also printed differently.
This print was printed on a press.
You can tell by the absolutely clean and even surface that the print has made onto the piece of paper.
This large stretch of very even color is much easier to create using a press.
However, in this print, that was hand printed, you can see where certain elements, of a, painter leaves can come out from the print.
It's hand printed so there can be different pressures.
There's also color that's been added in to certain areas, and printed over top of it.
It gives you a lot more flexibility, when as we did today, we can pull back the piece of paper, and print it again and again, and really work into the print in a very patronly way.
It gives you two very different looks to the print.
This is facilitated not only by the paper, but also the method of print making.